swaddledesigns.com 2017-11-14

# Privacy Policy

Welcome to SwaddleDesigns. As a customer of SwaddleDesigns, your confidence and trust is very important. We work to protect your personal information and ensure the proper use of your personal information. We are committed to protecting your personal information in our possession. In order to maintain your trust, we want you to understand what personal information we may collect from you, how we use such information, and the options you have regarding our use of this information. 

In this policy, "personal information" means any information by which you can be identified or contacted, such as your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number. 

This Privacy Policy governs your experience in this website unless otherwise indicated. 

### Categories of Information

We collect personal information when communicating or interacting with you through SwaddleDesigns.com and SwaddleClub.com Some examples include:

  * registering for a shopping account, Wish List or Registry on our website
  * when you request that merchandise be sent to you or others, make purchases or returns with us, place an order with us online, via phone, e-mail or fax, or request a receipt or tracking information
  * processing and fulfilling orders you place and delivering packages
  * requesting a catalog or other content and communications from us or when offering recommendations to you
  * subscribing to SwaddleDesigns email newsletters and updates or other communications from us or managing your preferences with us
  * applying for an account with us
  * your Financial Account numbers when transacting with us
  * interacting with our websites or mobile sites, mobile applications and services
  * when you participate in any of our programs such as contests, sweepstakes, surveys, loyalty programs, registry programs etc.
  * through communications with you
  * contacting us with a comment, problem, or question

When you visit our websites we may also gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet Protocol (IP) addresses or other device identifiers, browser information, Internet Service Provider (ISP), operating system, location, date/time stamp and clickstream data. We may also collect personal information about you from other third parties, to make our future service and marketing efforts more efficient and personalized for you. We may combine all information we collect and we may use or share this information with our service providers. 

#### How We Use Your Information

We use the personal information that we and our service providers collect to conduct our business and to provide you with the best possible products, services and experience. We may collect and use your information to provide you products and services, notify you of product issues, process membership, registry and wish list requests when you apply and administer your participation in our programs, to respond to your questions or complaints, determine your satisfaction with our service, to personalize your experiences, to send you marketing communications and other information you have chosen to receive regarding our products, services, marketing or special events. We also use your personal information for our everyday business purposes such as security, payment processing, analytics, operations, reporting, and legal compliance. 

#### How We Share Your Information

To best personalize your experience, we may share your personal information with service providers that provide support services to us or that help us market our products and services, administer our programs, operations, fulfill your requests, surveys, contests, sweepstakes and product reviews, or provide you with membership information. Service providers, third parties who perform services on our behalf, are contractually restricted from using your information in any manner other than in helping us to provide you with the products and services available from SwaddleDesigns. We may also, in certain instances, disclose your personal information when we have reason to believe that it is necessary to identify you, contact you, to detect and protect you or us from fraud, manage information security or bring legal action to protect your rights or the rights of SwaddleDesigns or others. We may also disclose your personal information when you ask us to do so or when we believe it is required or permitted by law. 

#### Mobile Privacy

SwaddleDesigns offers mobile services and applications (commonly known as "mobile apps") that allow you to shop online, check product availability, or receive other information from SwaddleDesigns. All personal information collected by SwaddleDesigns via our mobile apps are protected by this Privacy Policy. 

#### Cookies and Other Like Technologies

Our website uses "cookie" and other similar web technology like web beacons. We use cookies and web beacons to identify your device, provide website user authentication, conduct fraud prevention and management services, distinguish you from other visitors, record your IP address and understand your use of our site, and identify the name of the Web site from which you linked to SwaddleDesigns. This information is used for fulfilling contracts with our business partners, and to help us serve you better by improving our website design, as well as our products, services, and promotions. We do not otherwise track any information about your use of other websites. Information obtained through cookies and web beacons may be shared with or obtained by service providers on our behalf. 

A cookie is a small data file that is placed on the drive of your computer when you visit a website. A "session cookie" expires immediately when you end your session. A "persistent cookie" stores information on the hard drive so when you end your session and return to the same website at a later date, the cookie information is still available. A web beacon is a small string of code that represents a clear graphic image and is used in conjunction with a cookie. When you visit our website, we may use both a session and a persistent cookie. This SwaddleDesigns-placed cookie may contain information that is used to track your usage of our website and in some cases, your e-mail address. Your e-mail address is only saved in this SwaddleDesigns-placed cookie if you register with us. A web beacon allows us to capture certain additional types of information about a visitor's actions on a web site, such as a visitor's cookie number, the time, date, duration and number of page views, a description of the page where the Web beacon is placed, and details about any items that were purchased. 

If you register with us, this SwaddleDesigns-placed cookie allows us to recognize you when you return to our website and provides you with access to your account information. If you save your information with or order from us, we may also use cookies to monitor and maintain information about your use of our website. If you have not saved your information with or ordered from us, we may monitor and maintain information about your use of our website in a manner that does not identify you. You can disable cookies at any time by using your browser options; however, if you turn off cookies, we will not be able to track your order or enable you to make a purchase from our website. In addition, we will not be able to recognize you as a registered user to allow you access to your account information. 

#### Third-Party Advertising Partners

SwaddleDesigns uses third-party service providers to serve advertisements on our behalf across the Internet. 

These advertising service providers may collect non-identifiable information about your visits to our website, and your interactions with our products and services. Such non-identifiable information does not include your name, address, e-mail address or other personal information. The information is collected through the use of cookies and pixel tags which are industry-standard technology used by most major websites. 

In addition to the information about your visits to our website, our service providers may also use the information about your visits to other websites to target advertisements for products and services available from SwaddleDesigns. Currently, we use third party-placed tracking pixels and cookies from the following advertising delivery partner: AdRoll. In the future we may partner with other companies to provide interest-based advertising, both on and off SwaddleDesigns.com. If this occurs, SwaddleDesigns provides you with an opportunity to opt out when these advertisements are served. You may manage your third-party advertising preferences by clicking to opt out. 

#### Facebook Custom Audience Ads from SwaddleDesigns

We may display interest-based ads to you when you are using Facebook through a tool offered by Facebook called the Custom Audience Tool. This tool allows us to personalize our ads based on your shopping experience with us. We do not share any of your personal information, including your shopping history, with Facebook. The tool lets SwaddleDesigns convert your e-mail address to a unique number that Facebook uses to match to unique numbers Facebook generates from e-mail addresses of its users. You may opt-out of Facebook Custom Audience ads from SwaddleDesigns. 

#### Social Media Interactions

SwaddleDesigns invites you to socialize and share your favorite designs and purchases with your friends using Social Media tools such as Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest and Instagram. If you choose to use these tools, you may be sharing certain profile elements, including your comments. This sharing is subject to each social media program's privacy policies. We also use Facebook Social Plugins to allow Facebook to share information and friends' activities with its members while they are on our website. For example, Social Plugins allow Facebook to show you and your friends' "Likes" on our product pages if you are logged into Facebook while shopping at SwaddleDesigns.com. SwaddleDesigns does not receive or control any of the content from Facebook Social Plugins. To remove a Facebook "Like" through SwaddleDesigns, place your cursor in the "grayed out" Like button and click on the "X" that appears. This removes the "Like" from your Facebook Page, as well as from SwaddleDesigns websites. You can also delete comments made while at SwaddleDesigns.com from your Facebook Page. 

For more information about Facebook Social Plugins and other social media tools, click here. 

We may allow you to sign in to your SwaddleDesigns.com account using Facebook Connect. If you choose to do this, we may collect information necessary to facilitate social interactions such as friend lists, birthday, check-ins, basic profile information and your profile picture but only if the privacy settings you and your friends set within Facebook allow it. We will use the information we collect to create and facilitate an interactive social experience and to bring you products, services and programs from SwaddleDesigns. SwaddleDesigns will always comply both with its privacy policy as well as with Facebook Connect terms regarding use of Facebook profile information. 

#### Links to Other Websites and Services

Websites provided by SwaddleDesigns may include links to other Internet sites, content, or videos (embedded or direct links) maintained by third parties ('Linked Sites'). SwaddleDesigns provides Linked Sites to you solely as a convenience, and the inclusion of Linked Sites does not imply endorsement by SwaddleDesigns of the Linked Sites. You access Linked Sites at your own risk and by accessing them you leave SwaddleDesigns website. Linked Sites are not under the control of SwaddleDesigns and SwaddleDesigns is not responsible for the contents of any Linked Site, including the privacy policies or tracking technologies they may use. We encourage you to check the applicable privacy policy to determine how they will handle any personally identifying information they collect from you. 

#### Your Information, Your Choice

To update us with your preferences, you may contact us using one of the following methods:

  * Call 1-855-792-3353, or
  * E-mail privacy@SwaddleDesigns.com, or
  * Send your request to SwaddleDesigns, 500 Andover Park East, Seattle, WA 98188

Please note your preference as stated below:   
"I request not to receive e-mail advertisements, such as updates regarding products and services, special promotions or upcoming events." (You may also click the designated link at the bottom of all SwaddleDesigns.com e-mail newsletters and advertisements to be removed from future e-mail updates.) 

"I request not to receive direct mail advertisements, such as periodic catalogs and mailings regarding products and services, special promotions or upcoming events." (Please note that direct mail requests may take up to six to eight weeks to become effective.) 

#### Your Access

We respect your need to be able to access and update the personal information that you have provided to us. If you have registered online, you may access and update your personal information at any time by logging into your account. You may also request access and update your personal information by e-mail or writing to the SwaddleDesigns Privacy Office at the contact information set out below (subject to certain exceptions and as prescribed by law). We may request certain personal information to verify the identity of the individual seeking access to their personal information records. 

#### California Privacy Rights

California law entitles residents to ask us for a notice describing what categories of personal information we share with third parties or with affiliates for those entities direct marketing purposes. SwaddleDesigns does not provide any personal information to third parties for their own direct marketing purposes. If you want to request a notice or have any questions about SwaddleDesigns privacy practices, please contact us at privacy@SwaddleDesigns.com. 

#### Children's Privacy

SwaddleDesigns will never knowingly request or collect personal information from any person under 13 years of age without prior verifiable parental consent. If you are under 13 years old please do not provide your information on our website. 

If we become aware that an individual is under the age of 13 and has submitted any information to SwaddleDesigns for any purpose without prior verifiable parental consent, we will delete his or her information from our files. Security 

We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect the confidentiality and security of personal information transmitted to us using this website. To help guard your information, our website uses Secure Sockets Layer (SSL). SSL encrypts your credit card number, name and address so only SwaddleDesigns is able to decode your information. Please note that e-mail is not encrypted and is not considered to be a secure means of transmitting credit card information. 

To be sure your connection is secure, look at the bottom status bar of your browser window. If you see an unbroken key or a closed lock (depending on your browser) the SSL is active and your information is secure. Most browsers offer additional security alerts as well. If for some reason you are unable to connect to our secure server, please call us toll free at 1-855-SWADDLE. 

We also ask customers to carefully review their accounts and immediately report any unexpected activity to SwaddleDesigns and their issuing bank or credit card company. Additionally, we are asking all our customers to take measures to help protect personal information in their online accounts, including the following:

  * Install the latest security updates and anti-virus software on your computer to help prevent malware and viruses
  * Use complex passwords (a minimum of 6 alpha/numeric cAsE sEnsitive characters)
  * Do not use the same password on more than one website
  * Do not share your password with others
  * Sign out/log off website sessions so that your session is closed and cannot be accessed by another user on the same computer, especially when using a public computer or terminal
  * Visit these additional resources:
    * http://www.us-cert.gov/cas/tips/
    * http://www.microsoft.com/security/pc-security/protect-pc.aspx
    * http://www.clarkhoward.com/news/clark-howard/technology/clark-howards-virus-spyware-and-malware-protection/nFZJ/

#### Data Processing and Storage

SwaddleDesigns and its third party service providers may process or store your personal information outside of the United States or Canada and other countries. In accordance with the laws of those countries, in certain circumstances your personal information may be accessible by foreign law enforcement, regulatory bodies or other authorities. For more information of our use of foreign service providers please contact us as described below. 

#### International Customer Privacy

Protecting the privacy and security of SwaddleDesigns customer information is a top priority for SwaddleDesigns. In some cases, SwaddleDesigns partners with outside vendors to help facilitate transactions. When that is the case, we work closely with the vendor to ensure that the transaction is appropriately handled and all the information you provide is treated with the utmost care. 

#### Business Transitions

As we continue to develop our business, we may undergo a business transition such as acquiring another company, merging with an existing company, or selling a portion of our assets. In such transitions, customer information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. In the unlikely event that SwaddleDesigns, LLC or substantially all of its assets are acquired or enter a court proceeding, you acknowledge that such transfers may occur and that your personal information can continue to be used as set forth in this Privacy Policy. 

#### Policy Changes

This policy replaces all previous disclosures we may have provided you about our information practices. We reserve the right to change this policy, and to apply any changes to information previously collected, as permitted by law. If there are material changes to this policy or our information practices change in the future, we will notify you by posting the policy changes on our website. 

#### Additional Information

If you're not comfortable shopping online (and would prefer to make your purchase via telephone), just give us a call at 1-855-SWADDLE. Our customer service team will be delighted to assist you. For your convenience, SwaddleDesigns may link to unaffiliated third party websites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to unaffiliated third party websites. 

If you have questions regarding our Privacy Policy please contact us at:   
SwaddleDesigns Privacy  
480 Andover Park East  
Seattle, WA 98188  
privacy@SwaddleDesigns.com 

The examples contained in this Privacy Policy are illustrations and not intended to be exhaustive. 

Updated on January 24, 2014
